A Motion Picture with a stirring message on Marriage! A
Powerful Film, full of truths of life and love!
The Crowd is a drama, romance film directed by King Vidor.
John, an ambitious but undisciplined New York City
office worker, meets and marries Mary.
They start a family, struggle to cope with marital stress, financial setbacks, and
tragedy, all while lost amid the anonymous, pitiless throngs of the big city.
Mary Sims, played by Eleanor Boardman.
John 'Johnny' Sims, played by James Murray.
Bert, played by Bert Roach.
Jane, played by Estelle Clark.
Jim, played by Daniel G. Tomlinson.
Dick, played by Dell Henderson.
The Crowd is a 1928 American silent drama film directed by King Vidor and
starring James Murray, Eleanor Boardman and Bert Roach.
The feature film was nominated at the first Academy Award presentation in 1929 for several
awards, including Unique and Artistic Production for MGM and Best Director for Vidor.
Kevin Brownlow and David Gill restored The Crowd in 1981, and
it was released with a score by Carl Davis.
In 1989, the film was one of the first 25 selected by the Library of Congress for preservation in the United
States National Film Registry for being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
In February 2020, the film was shown at the 70th Berlin International Film
Festival, as part of a retrospective dedicated to Vidor's career.
The film entered the public domain in the United States in 2024.
The film explores themes of new york city, marriage, tragedy, silent film.
The tone is emotional.